Guide to the David Feldshuh papers, 1984-2006
Feldshuh, David papers,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
David Feldshuh papers, 1984-2006
14-24-3458
David, Feldshuh 1944-
6.5 cubic ft.
{comma separted list of material formats; end with period.}
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Professional papers and reviews, newspaper clippings, correpondence, and programs for various plays, including Miss Evers' Boys, a play based on the notorious Tuskegee Syphilis Study in the African American male.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of Theatre Arts and Director of the Cornell Center for Theatre Arts.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Professional papers and reviews, newspaper clippings, correpondence, and programs for various plays, including Miss Evers' Boys, a play based on the notorious Tuskegee Syphilis Study in the African American male.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Feldshuh, David,1944-; Tuskegee Syphilis Study.; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University.Dept. of Theatre Arts
Subjects:
Human experimentation in medicine--Alabama--Macon County--History.; African American men--Diseases--Alabama--Macon County--History.; Syphilis--Research--Alabama--Macon County--History.; Theater--Study and teaching.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Institutes and Foundations
Series II. Newspaper Articles and Reviews
Series III. Programs and Study Guides
Series IV. Theaters and Productions
Series V. Scripts, Reviews, & Press Packets
Series VI. Department Files
Series VII. Theatre Cornell
Series VIII. Miss Evers' Boys Files
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Institutes and Foundations
  - Sundance Institute: Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Sundance Institute: Newsletters and Articles (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Dodge Foundation: Dodge Award (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Dodge Foundation: Information and Congratulations (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Dodge Foundation: Contract Agreement and Check Award (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Dodge Foundation: Publicity (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Series II. Newspaper Articles and Reviews
  - Reference 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Reference 2 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Reference 3 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Tuskegee Archives Material (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - The Times of London: Article, August 8, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - The Atlanta Journal: Article, September 6, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Mark Taper Forum (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous Articles (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Alabama Shakespheare Festival (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Alley Theatre (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Alliance/Time (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - American Conservatory Theatre (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Birmingham 1991 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Center Stage (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - City Theatre Company (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Washington Post (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Cornell (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Cornell (2) (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Ithaca Journal (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Dartmouth Medical Magazine, June 1992 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Series III. Programs and Study Guides
  - Alabama Shakespeare Festival (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Alley Theatre Programs (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Alliance Programs (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - American Conservatory Theatre (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Birmingham Repertory Theatre (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Buffalo Studio Arena Theatre (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - City Theatre Company (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Center Stage Programs (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Dallas Theatre Center (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Detroit Repertory Theatre (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Fulton Opera House (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Goodman Theatre Programs (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Illusion Programs (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Illusion Programs 1991 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - L.A. Programs (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Miscellaneous Programs and Playbills, Up to 2009 (Box 7)
- Series IV. Theaters and Productions
  - Copies of Research for New Theaters
    - Copies of Research for New Theaters (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Copies of Research for New Theaters I (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Copies of Research for New Theaters II (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Goodman Theatre (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Detroit Repertory Theatre (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Dallas Theatre Center (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Illusion (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - MEB New York Production (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Alliance (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - American Conservatory Theater (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Indianapolis (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Mixed Packets (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - L.A. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - St. Louis Repertory Theatre (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Philidelphia Theatre Company (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Pittsburgh, City Theatre (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Fulton Opera House (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Center Stage (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Ensemble Theatre, Cleveland (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Indiana Repertory Theatre (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Charlotte Rep. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Buffalo Studio Arena Theatre (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Birmingham Repertory Theatre (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Alabama Shakespeare Festival (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - MEB Cornell Production (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Cinn. Playhouse (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Kansas City Midwest Bioethics (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Madison Repertory Theatre (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Phoenix (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Tacoma Actor's Guild (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Series V. Scripts, Reviews, & Press Packets
  - TCG Script (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Miss Evers' Boys Script/American Mag. Galleys (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Masters: Miss Evers' Boys Reviews (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Los Angeles Reviews (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Minneapolis Reviews (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Baltimore Reviews (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Atlanta Reviews (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Misc. Reviews (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Miss Evers' Boys Reviews (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Miss Evers' Boys: Press Packets (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Miss Evers' Boys: Morality At Play (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - An Italian Straw Hat, Expression (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - A Christmas Carol, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Fables Here and There, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 4-6)
  - The Marriage of Bette and Boo, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 7-8)
  - Mysteries of Eleusis, 1986-05 (Box 8, Folder 9-10)
  - Cinders, 1987-08 (Box 8, Folder 11-14)
  - Cyrano, 1990-05 (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
  - King Lear background and Research, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 3-4)
  - King Lear photographs, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - King Lear, 1993-04 (Box 9, Folder 6-9)
  - The House of Blue Leaves, 1994-09 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Fetu and her Friends, 1994-10 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Measure for Measure, 1995-11 (Box 9, Folder 12-14)
  - Measure for Measure, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 1-3)
  - Perestroika, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 4-6)
  - Army Screenplay, 1996-1997 (Box 10, Folder 7-8)
  - You Never Can Tell, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Death of a Salesman Analysis, 1997-09 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - The Prime of Miss Jean Brodie, 1999-09 (Box 10, Folder 11-12)
    Contains letter from director Sam Gold.
  - Cat on a Hot Tin Roof, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
  - Amadeus, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 3-4)
  - Matchmaker, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 5-6)
  - Arturo Ui, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 7-8)
  - Antigone, 2003 (Box 11, Folder 9-12)
  - The Cradle Will Rock, 2005 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - The Cradle Will Rock, 2005 (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
  - The Merchant of Venice, 2005 (Box 12, Folder 3-5)
  - All my Sons, 2006 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Metamorphses, 2006 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Dracula, 2008 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Mass, 2009 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Mass: Original score, 2009 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Mass: summaries, script, dance, 2009 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Mass: editing, agendas, talk throughs, 2009 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Mass: children staging, street chorus, reviews and articles, 2009 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Nice People, 2009 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Mass: rehearsal schedules, directors notes, 2009 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Mass: celebrant, religion, short talk throughs, 2009 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Mass: projections, staging, character agenda/character and song, 2009 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Mass: budget, liturgical choir, design (k Goetz), program notes, 2009 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Mass: images, contacts, publicity, props/costumes, 2009 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Mass: viewpoints/POV, music/soloists, research, production meetings, 2009 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - On the Verge, 2015 (Box 13, Folder 7-9)
  - Eurydice, 2016 (Box 13, Folder 10-12)
- Series VI. Department Files
  - Production Personnel, 1995-2000 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Undergraduate Actors: Personnel List from General Auditions, September 9-10, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Undergraduate Roles by Minorities (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Production Assignments, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - RPTA Auditions 1, 1991-2000 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    All RPTA Audition files include comp photos and evaluation sheets, resumes and contact information
  - RPTA Auditions 2, 1991-2000 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - RPTA Auditions 3, 1991-2000 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - RPTA, 1991-1995 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - RPTA, 1996- (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Awards: Drama Bookshop Awards, 1986-1988 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Mellon Foundation, c.1988 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - A.R.T. New York, Programs and Services, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Cornell University Membership Card
  - Bean Fellowship (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - (FD 1) Hollywood Connection (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - (FD 2) Staffing Needs (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - (FD 3) Endowable Opp. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - (FD 4) PAC Fundraising (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - National Theatre of Great Britain: Press Announcements (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - National Theatre of Great Britain: Course Suggestions (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - National Theatre of Great Britain: Budget (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - National Theatre of Great Britain: Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - National Theatre of Great Britain: National/CU Summer Theatre Program (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - National Theatre of Great Britain: Faculty (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Harold Bank Fund (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Black History Month: Cast Me Down Productions, Inc. (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Eissner Committee (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Exploration Series (Box 3, Folder 27)
    Program, John Guare's "The Loveliest Afternoon of the Year and a Day For Surprises", component of the Exploration Series
  - Outreach 1 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    RPTA Presentations, "Stop Date Rape", abbreviated scripts, press releases, human relations training, etc.
  - Outreach 2: RPTA Presentations (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Outreach 3 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - PR Outreach Plays, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Cornell Sesquicentennial planning, 2011-2015 (Box 13, Folder 13-14)
  - Season planning, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Season planning, 2006 (Box 13, Folder 16-17)
  - Season planning, 2002-2009 (Box 13, Folder 18)
- Series VII. Theatre Cornell
  - Playwritting (Box 3, Folder 32-40)
  - Speeches (Box 3, Folder 41-48)
  - A Cole Porter Cabaret (Box 3, Folder 49-52)
  - Theater Classroom Project (Box 3, Folder 53-56)
  - Press (Box 3, Folder 57-58)
  - Articles (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - April 10 Event (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Index (Box 3, Folder 61)
- Series VIII. Miss Evers' Boys Files
  - Volume 1 and Volume 2, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Scripts (Box 4, Folder 2)
    American Conservatory, Alley Theatre, Madison Rep. Theatre, Geraldine R. Dodge Thatre Program, and typed script
  - Script revisions (2 finished scripts) (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Ideas and Structures, Acts I-III (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - MEB Research and Notes (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - MEB Research (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Final: May 7, 1994, May 1994 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Rougns (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Swan Dance, July 1989 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Medical Research (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Bad Blood (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Dance (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Scene Notes (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Brodus (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - PCT and 2 of 3 Prep (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Testimony (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Act III Rough (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Act II Rough (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - MEB Script and Notes (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Reasearch (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - CME Master Copy and other copy (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Notes and Scripts (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Script Notes, Journal, Slides, Film (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Draft 10 - Annotated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Script with Notes (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Script with Notes (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Drafts 1, 2, 15 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Rough Draft 1 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Script, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Miss Evers' Boys drafts, 10/1991 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Miss Evers' Boys notes, 3/17/1992 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Miss Evers' Boys drafts, 8, 10/1992 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Miss Evers' Boys, 10/15/1992 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Miss Evers' Boys drafts, 1, 5/1994 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Miss Evers' Boys final #2, 10/15/1992 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Miss Evers' Boys HBO screenplay, 1994-1995 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Miss Evers' Boys HBO screenplay, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Miss Evers' Boys Goodman Theatre, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Inauguration speech outlines, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Inauguration speech notes, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Inauguration speech drafts #1-#19, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 12-30)
  - Inauguration speech final draft, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Inauguration materials, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Inauguration: notes and e-mails, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Inauguration: press and photos, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Inauguration: logistics, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Miss Evers' Boys poster, Undated (Mapcase-folder 1)
  - Season planning, 2002-2009 (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
  - Who's Afraid of Virginia Wolf?, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 3-6)
  - Trials of Brother Jero, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 7-9)
  - Mouther Courage, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 10-15)
  - A Midsummer's Dream, Undated (Box 14, Folder 16-20)